I did use you.
나는 당신을 이용했습니다.
But when I saw you,
그런데 내가 당신을 봤을 때,
to see you.
너를보기 위해.
What about you?
당신은 어때요?
Are you happy?
행복하니?
I knew it.
알고 있었어.
I don't want you to be involved.
나는 당신이 관여하는 것을 원하지 않습니다.
I want you to leave safely.
무사히 떠나셨으면 좋겠습니다.
Why do you still want to marry me?
왜 아직도 나와 결혼하고 싶어?
You won't go?
안 갈 거야?
I think
제 생각에는
I'll fulfill my promise to you.
나는 당신과의 약속을 이행할 것입니다.
Really?
정말?
But if I marry you,
하지만 내가 당신과 결혼한다면,
It's just to kill Yamashita.
바로 야마시타를 죽이는 것뿐이다.
Will you believe it?
당신은 그것을 믿을 것인가?
He would.
그는 것.
No matter what.
무슨 일이 있어도.
Do you think I love you?
내가 당신을 사랑한다고 생각하세요?
Certainly.
틀림없이.
You should be confident of yourself.
당신은 자신에 대해 자신감을 가져야합니다.
Look how proud you are.
당신이 얼마나 자랑스러워하는지보세요.
You're really something.
당신은 정말 대단해요.
I thought you were killed by Officer Uchida.
나는 당신이 우치다 경관에게 살해당한 줄 알았습니다.
I was trying to save myself.
나는 나 자신을 구하려고 노력했습니다.
I told Ueda that
나는 우에다에게 그렇게 말했다.
as long as I follow Wang Dapu,
내가 왕다푸를 따라가는 한,
we might have a chance to get the copper plate.
우리가 동판을 얻을 기회가 있을지도 몰라요.
Uchida trusts you.
우치다는 당신을 신뢰합니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
He trusts me more than you do.
그 사람은 당신보다 나를 더 신뢰해요.
Is he mad at me?
그 사람 나한테 화났나?
The Japanese gave the order.
일본인이 명령을 내렸습니다.
If I don't hand you over to the Imperial Prison, OK?
내가 당신을 제국 감옥에 넘겨주지 않으면 알겠죠?
That's right, Jiaping.
그렇구나, 자핑.
Look at yourself.
너 자신을 봐.
You were put in the detention center.
당신은 구치소에 갇혔습니다.
But the Japanese never tortured you.
그러나 일본인은 결코 당신을 고문하지 않았습니다.
They are all people, Manager Luo.
모두 사람이에요, 루오 매니저님.
To help you
당신을 돕기 위해
to plead for you.
당신을 위해 간청합니다.
Look at this.
이거 봐요.
Shuangtao defended me.
Shuangtao가 나를 변호했습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Look at this.
이거 봐요.
All right.
괜찮은.
I know you are wronged.
나는 당신이 부당한 대우를 받고 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
I will
그럴게요
I'll hold a banquet for you
내가 당신을 위해 연회를 열게요
get rid of the old to make way for the new
새로운 것을 만들기 위해 오래된 것을 제거하십시오
by the way, Luo,
그런데 루오,
how is the business recently?
최근 사업은 어때요?
Still the same.
여전히 동일합니다.
Without Zhao An,
자오안이 없으면,
this is much quieter.
이것은 훨씬 더 조용합니다.
That's strange.
이상하다.
Zhao An has so many lives.
조안(Zhao An)은 인생이 너무 많습니다.
How can he be the five of hearts?
그는 어떻게 다섯 마음이 될 수 있습니까?
How many lives
얼마나 많은 삶
of Wang Tianmu's hands?
왕티안무의 손?
We've already pledged our allegiance here.
우리는 이미 이곳에서 충성을 맹세했습니다.
That's right.
좋아요.
Now,
지금,
zhao An has finally pulled out the candle.
자오안은 마침내 촛불을 꺼냈다.
From now on, Taihe Trading Firm
이제부터 태화무역회사
will be controlled by us.
우리가 통제할 것입니다.
Do you remember Xiucai Qian who guarded the door?
문을 지키고 있던 Xiucai Qian을 기억하시나요?
Even he
심지어 그 사람도
want to seek help from me.
나에게 도움을 구하고 싶어요.
And work for me.
그리고 나를 위해 일해주세요.
Many people nowadays
요즘 많은 사람들이
they should know about themselves.
그들은 자기 자신에 대해 알아야 합니다.
Qian Xiucai,
첸 슈카이,
by the way,
그런데,
copper coins of the Communist Party of China
중국 공산당의 구리 동전
the copper coins?
구리 동전?
I didn't only see
나만 본게 아니었어
at the same time.
동시에.
The Japanese have been dying for this.
일본인들은 이것 때문에 죽어가고 있습니다.
A combination of military damage and economic damage.
군사적 피해와 경제적 피해가 결합된 형태입니다.
It seems that the Japanese executives
일본 임원인거 같은데
has changed their thinking.
그들의 생각이 바뀌었습니다.
What a pity!
정말 안타깝습니다!
If I can get this bronze plate,
만약 내가 이 청동판을 얻을 수 있다면,
let alone this is your car,
이 차는 말할 것도 없고,
I didn't even bother to sit in Naoki Uchida's car.
나는 우치다 나오키의 차에 앉을 생각조차 하지 않았다.
You only talk big things.
큰 얘기만 하시네요.
Think about our future.
우리의 미래에 대해 생각해 보세요.
Now Japan and the United States are going to war.
이제 일본과 미국이 전쟁을 벌이게 됩니다.
I'm afraid it's inevitable.
불가피한 일이 아닐까 걱정됩니다.
The situation
그 상황
the situation in the future.
앞으로의 상황.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Shuangtao.
솽타오.
Go back and have a rest
돌아가서 쉬세요
I have a few more words with Jiaping.
Jiaping과 몇 마디 더 말씀드리겠습니다.
Newspaper. Newspaper.
신문. 신문.
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
I know you are wronged.
나는 당신이 부당한 대우를 받고 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
Have a good rest.
편안히 휴식을 취하다.
Don't go to work in a hurry.
서둘러 출근하지 마세요.
There's another thing.
또 다른 것이 있습니다.
I made a deal recently.
최근에 거래를 했어요.
I have to find someone I'm trustworthy.
믿을 수 있는 사람을 찾아야 해요.
Someone you trust.
당신이 신뢰하는 사람.
Well, there?
음, 거기?
The big spoon doesn't work well.
큰 숟가락은 잘 안 써요.
I still need you the most.
나는 아직도 당신이 가장 필요합니다.
What deal?
무슨 거래요?
I'll tell you when.
언제인지 말씀드리겠습니다.
But you have to remember
하지만 기억해야 해
what I told you in the car.
내가 차에서 말한 것.
The Japanese are unreliable now.
이제 일본인은 신뢰할 수 없습니다.
We have to think about our own future.
우리는 우리 자신의 미래에 대해 생각해야 합니다.
You're making it sound unclear.
불분명하게 들리게 만드네요.
But I'm telling you that
하지만 나는 당신에게 이렇게 말하고 있어요
don't think I'll forgive you.
내가 당신을 용서할 거라고 생각하지 마세요.
Have a good rest.
편안히 휴식을 취하다.
I can understand now.
이제 이해할 수 있습니다.
To protect your identity,
귀하의 신원을 보호하기 위해,
you secretly helped me.
당신은 몰래 나를 도왔습니다.
I thought they got information
정보를 얻은 줄 알았는데
we got the information from you.
우리는 당신으로부터 정보를 얻었습니다.
For example, the time you saved people in Hongyun Hotel.
예를 들면 홍윤호텔에서 사람을 구한 때.
Were leaked to me on purpose.
일부러 나한테 유출한거임
You have helped me before.
당신은 전에 나를 도왔습니다.
Just like the time that you killed Feng Qi.
당신이 Feng Qi를 죽였을 때와 같습니다.
Without your evidence,
당신의 증거 없이,
I wouldn't have
나는하지 않았을 것이다
just confirm Feng Qi's crime.
Feng Qi의 범죄를 확인하십시오.
Do you think
당신은 생각합니까?
are we different bedfellows?
우리는 서로 다른 동료인가요?
It is.
그것은.
But that doesn't count
하지만 그건 중요하지 않아
even the dream of our couple
우리 부부의 꿈까지도
will eventually come together.
결국 함께하게 될 것입니다.
So you brought back
그래서 다시 데려오셨어요
some files about the CPC
CPC에 관한 일부 파일
he wanted me to see
그 사람은 내가 보고 싶어 했어
Including the files of Lu.
Lu의 파일을 포함합니다.
Gave a lot of thought to this.
이것에 대해 많은 생각을했습니다.
Back then, I made up my mind
그때 나는 마음을 먹었다.
to win you over.
당신을 이기기 위해.
But I can't be honest with you.
하지만 나는 당신에게 솔직하게 말할 수 없습니다.
So I can only
그래서 나는 단지
In a subtle way.
미묘한 방법으로.
I have to say that
나는 그것을 말해야한다
you've been very helpful
당신은 매우 도움이 되었습니다
the ideological work.
이념적 작업.
Because I know you.
나는 당신을 알고 있기 때문에.
I know you.
나는 당신을 알고 있습니다.
What kind of person you want to be.
당신은 어떤 사람이 되고 싶은가?
Think about
생각해 보세요
the one where our respective missions
우리 각자의 임무가 있는 곳
Is that Ci'an Hospital?
거기가 시안병원인가요?
You must have been following the clue to the magpie.
당신은 까치의 단서를 따라가고 있었나 봐요.
That's why you appeared there.
그래서 당신이 거기 나타난 거죠.
That's right.
좋아요.
We're investigating
우리는 조사 중입니다
the formula of the paper used for the coin currency stolen by Juntong spies
준통 간첩이 훔친 동전 화폐에 사용되는 종이의 공식
and the copper plate.
그리고 동판.
Now thinking back,
지금 생각해보면,
you are really good at acting.
당신은 연기를 정말 잘해요.
She knew about my identity,
그녀는 내 정체를 알고 있었고,
but pretended to be scared.
하지만 겁먹은 척 했어요.
If a man can act,
남자가 행동할 수 있다면,
he must be forced by your women.
그는 당신의 여자에 의해 강요되어야합니다.
And confess yourself like this?
그리고 이렇게 고백해?
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
How many other dramas and lies
얼마나 많은 드라마와 거짓말이
and how many lies you told me.
그리고 당신이 나에게 얼마나 많은 거짓말을했는지.
I swear.
맹세해요.
Aside from my identity,
내 신분과는 별개로,
about my identity.
내 정체성에 대해.
I don't believe that.
나는 그것을 믿지 않습니다.
When a man lies,
남자가 거짓말을 하면,
It's only the first and countless times.
그것은 처음이자 셀 수 없이 많은 일이다.
You've lied to me before.
당신은 전에 나에게 거짓말을 한 적이 있습니다.
That's different.
그건 달라.
Women lie
여자들은 거짓말을 한다
so that men won't be sad.
남자들이 슬퍼하지 않도록.
When a man lies,
남자가 거짓말을 하면,
Is purely to lie to women.
순전히 여자들에게 거짓말을 하는 것입니다.
What kind of nonsense are you talking about?
무슨 말도 안되는 소리를하고 있습니까?
You intentionally exposed yourself that day,
그날 일부러 노출을 시키셨는데,
so you could join us
그래서 당신도 우리와 함께 할 수 있어요
to raid the counterfeit factory with us?
우리와 함께 위조품 공장을 급습하러 갈까요?
I only saw that there is so much evidence
증거가 너무 많다는 걸 봤어요
and you didn't have a reason to think so
그리고 당신은 그렇게 생각할 이유가 없었어요
and became anxious.
그리고 불안해졌습니다.
Of course,
물론,
the most important thing is your safety.
가장 중요한 것은 당신의 안전입니다.
The last sentence
마지막 문장
really touches me.
정말 감동적이에요.
Did you start to suspect me
나를 의심하기 시작했나요?
after that operation?
그 수술 후에?
I should've doubted you,
난 당신을 의심했어야 했는데,
but I didn't expect that
하지만 난 그럴 줄은 몰랐어
that Zhao An replaced it.
Zhao An이 그 자리를 대신했습니다.
It was a nice design.
좋은 디자인이었습니다.
What do you mean by that?
그게 무슨 뜻 이니?
Did you think
생각 했습니까
that I should be inferior to you?
내가 너보다 열등해야 한다고?
I didn't say that.
나는 그렇게 말하지 않았다.
Otherwise, I won't let you know more
그렇지 않으면 더 이상 알려 주지 않겠습니다.
the Communist Party's anti-Japanese actions
공산당의 항일행위
and the communist ideology.
그리고 공산주의 이념.
I don't know either
나도 모르겠어요
I know you well enough.
나는 당신을 충분히 잘 알고 있습니다.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
It's enough for you to know me
당신이 나를 아는 것만으로도 충분해요
knowing me
나를 아는 것
and you know us.
그리고 당신은 우리를 알고 있습니다.
I have now completely broken
이제 완전히 망가졌어
with Juntong.
준통이랑.
Would you accept an ex-military unification member?
통일군 출신을 받아들이시겠습니까?
I'll testify for you!
내가 당신을 위해 증언하겠습니다!
You're not like Jiang Zhaoguo and the others.
당신은 Jiang Zhaoguo와 다른 사람들과는 다릅니다.
You always insisted
넌 항상 주장했지
our call for unity
우리의 단결 요구
that we have called for.
우리가 요청한 것입니다.
Your thoughts and actions
당신의 생각과 행동
In thought and action.
생각과 행동에서.
I'm ready.
난 준비됐어.
Alright.
괜찮은.
I'll report to the organization as soon as possible
최대한 빨리 해당 기관에 보고하겠습니다.
so that one day,
그래서 어느 날,
that we can all
우리 모두 할 수 있다고
as soon as possible.
최대한 빨리.
I'm looking forward to that day to come.
나는 그날이 오기를 고대하고 있습니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
But we need to be more careful
하지만 우리는 좀 더 조심해야 해요
while waiting.
기다리는 동안.
After all, you've taken away the copper plate from Jiang Zhaoguo.
결국 당신은 Jiang Zhaoguo에게서 동판을 빼앗 았습니다.
He must be
그는 반드시
he must be so exasperated that
그 사람이 너무 화가 나서 그랬나 봐요
assassination.
암살.
That's what he did.
그것이 그가 한 일입니다.
I know how they are.
나는 그들이 어떤지 압니다.
They can't handle me.
그들은 나를 감당할 수 없습니다.
Now we have the copper plate.
이제 구리판이 생겼습니다.
When we find the paper formula of the coin,
동전의 종이 공식을 찾으면,
the real counterfeit factory
진짜 위조공장
my mission is over.
내 임무는 끝났어.
I've got to finish
난 끝내야 해
with you.
너와 함께.
Four of clubs,
4개의 클럽,
five of hearts.
하트 다섯 개.
We're officially together.
우리는 공식적으로 함께 있어요.
Pay more attention to your safety.
안전에 더욱 주의하세요.
As for the business,
사업에 관해서는,
let's not go there.
거기 가지 말자.
I'll talk to Luo Guanqun
Luo Guanqun과 통화하겠습니다.
tell her that my wife worked so hard for me
내 아내가 나를 위해 너무 열심히 일했다고 말해주세요
and she's resting at home.
그리고 그 사람은 집에서 쉬고 있어요.
You should stay at home.
집에 있어야 해요.
I won't go anywhere.
나는 아무데도 가지 않을 것이다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
What about you?
당신은 어때요?
I have to...
나는 ...
I need to contact my superior.
상사에게 연락해야 해요.
Who is your superior?
당신의 상사는 누구입니까?
How do you usually contact?
보통 어떻게 연락하시나요?
My superior is...
내 상사는...
My superior is the Communist Party of China.
나의 상사는 중국공산당이다.
The way we communicate with each other
우리가 서로 소통하는 방식
that's a communist ideology.
그것은 공산주의 이념입니다.
That means he didn't say anything.
즉, 그는 아무 말도 하지 않았다는 뜻이다.
He still doesn't treat me as one of his own.
그는 아직도 나를 자신의 사람으로 대하지 않습니다.
The copper coin has been recovered.
구리 동전이 회수되었습니다.
Please indicate when and where to exchange the coins.
코인 교환 시기와 장소를 알려주세요.
In this operation,
이 작업에서는
In the operation.
수술 중.
She might not stay here for long.
그녀는 여기에 오래 머물지 못할 수도 있습니다.
Zuo Shuangtao has known my identity.
Zuo Shuangtao는 내 정체를 알고 있었습니다.
She has broken with Juntong
그녀는 준통과 헤어졌다
to join the underground organizations of our Party.
우리 당의 지하조직에 가입하기 위하여.
Please approve it.
승인해 주십시오.
Come in.
올.
Manager Luo,
루오 매니저님,
there is a response.
응답이 있습니다.
What about
는 어때
he agreed to our asking price.
그는 우리가 요구하는 가격에 동의했습니다.
Next,
다음,
one step at a time.
한 번에 한 단계 씩.
Follow the plan.
계획을 따르십시오.
Yes
예
nice to meet you, sir.
만나서 반가워요, 선생님.
I've booked a cafe on the second floor.
2층 카페를 예약했어요.
This way, please.
이쪽으로 오십시오.
902.
902.
The magpie is in 902.
까치는 902호에 있어요.
Hurry!
서두르다!
Yes
예
mister.
아저씨.
This place is sealed off.
이 장소는 봉쇄되어 있습니다.
Get out of here!
여기서 나가!
Let go of me!
날 놔줘!
We've searched every body.
우리는 모든 시체를 수색했습니다.
I didn't find anything.
나는 아무것도 찾지 못했습니다.
That's impossible.
그것은 불가능합니다.
I found something.
뭔가를 찾았어요.
The formula of the coin paper
동전 종이의 공식
Is on him.
그에게 있습니다.
Who's that?
저 사람은 누구야?
Who are you?
누구세요?
You don't want to tell me?
나한테 말하고 싶지 않아?
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
I don't know.
모르겠습니다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
What do you want?
당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
See that?
저거 봐?
Boss.
사장.
What to do with that magpie?
그 까치를 어떻게 해야 할까요?
Not to be worth a hair
머리카락 하나도 아깝지 않은
I suspect that the magpie
까치가 의심된다
hid the formula in her wound.
그녀의 상처 속에 분유를 숨겼어요.
So I opened it with a dagger.
그래서 단검으로 열어봤습니다.
But I didn't find it.
그러나 나는 그것을 찾지 못했습니다.
But I found a piece of brown paper.
그런데 갈색 종이 한 장을 발견했어요.
This proves my judgment is right.
이것은 내 판단이 옳았다는 것을 증명합니다.
But maybe someone
하지만 어쩌면 누군가
maybe someone took it earlier
어쩌면 누군가가 더 일찍 가져 갔을 수도 있습니다.
chief Chen
첸 수석
sit down
앉아
second Blade.
두 번째 블레이드.
Seeing me back,
나를 다시 보니,
right?
오른쪽?
How would I dare to be disappointed?
내가 어떻게 감히 실망할 수 있겠습니까?
I was so scared.
나는 너무 무서웠다.
No, I didn't mean that.
아뇨, 그런 뜻은 아니었어요.
We were surprised and happy
우리는 놀랐고 행복했습니다.
you also saw the ending
너도 엔딩 봤잖아
and Chen Dugu.
그리고 첸시티.
I've seen it.
나 그거 봤었 어.
Thanks to your wife, she alerted me.
당신의 아내 덕분에 그녀는 나에게 경고했습니다.
You didn't forget the task
당신은 임무를 잊지 않았습니다
I gave you, right?
내가 줬지? 응?
I wouldn't dare to forget it.
나는 그것을 감히 잊지 못할 것입니다.
I've been following Dazhao
다자오를 팔로우하고 있어요
any findings?
어떤 결과가 있습니까?
Tai Scoop has been acting abnormal recently.
Tai Scoop이 최근 이상하게 행동하고 있습니다.
He seems to be secretly contacting someone.
그는 누군가에게 몰래 연락을 하고 있는 것 같다.
But he was afraid to expose his whereabouts.
하지만 그는 자신의 행방이 드러나는 것을 두려워했다.
He changes a different phone booth
그는 다른 전화부스로 바뀐다
every time he calls.
그가 전화할 때마다.
That's it?
그게 다야?
I haven't finished.
아직 끝나지 않았습니다.
Big Scoop knows me.
Big Scoop은 나를 알고 있습니다.
I didn't dare to get too close to him.
나는 감히 그에게 너무 가까이 다가갈 수 없었습니다.
Later on,
나중에,
I paid off a beggar.
나는 거지에게 돈을 지불했습니다.
To approach him when he made the call.
그가 전화를 걸었을 때 그에게 접근하기 위해.
According to the beggar,
그 거지의 말에 따르면,
he was negotiating with the man on the phone about a price.
그는 전화로 그 남자와 가격을 협상하고 있었습니다.
He said he wanted 500 little yellow croakers
그는 작은 노랑 민어 500마리를 원한다고 하더군요
no one is missing.
아무도 실종되지 않았습니다.
Five hundred little yellow fishes?
작은 노란 물고기 500마리요?
That means 30 jin of gold!
그것은 금 30진을 의미합니다!
That's right.
좋아요.
I didn't know these treasures
난 이런 보물을 몰랐어
could be sold for so much.
그 만큼 팔릴 수도 있다.
Who's on the end of the phone?
전화 통화는 누구입니까?
Do you know
당신은 알고 있나요
I don't know.
모르겠습니다.
That's it?
그게 다야?
She even went to the camera shop.
그녀는 심지어 카메라 가게에도 갔다.
What?
무엇?
He bought a developing tank and fixing powder.
현상탱크와 고착분말을 구입했습니다.
Are you going to develop photos?
사진을 현상할 건가요?
Exactly.
정확히.
He even put the developed photos in an envelope
현상한 사진을 봉투에 넣어주기도 하더군요
the photos in an envelope.
봉투에 담긴 사진.
Who was it addressed to?
누구에게 전달되었나요?
That's right.
좋아요.
I remade the envelope.
봉투를 다시 만들었어요.
Look at this.
이거 봐요.
That's great.
훌륭해요.
How did you get this letter?
이 편지를 어떻게 받았어요?
That day, I followed Dashao
그날 나는 다샤오를 따라갔다.
I saw him putting a letter in the mailbox
나는 그가 우편함에 편지를 넣는 것을 봤어요
In An De Road.
안드로드에 있어요.
It was 8 in the morning
아침 8시였어요
I know the postman
나는 우체부를 안다
to pick up the mail at 9: 00 a.m.
오전 9시에 우편물을 찾으러
I used the one hour between that
그 사이에 1시간을 사용했어요
of the mailbox with this one hour
이 한 시간 동안 우편함을
and found the letter in no time
그리고 곧 편지를 찾았어
oh yeah
오 예
besides the envelope, I also recreated the photo.
봉투 외에 사진도 재현했어요.
I mean, where are you?
내 말은, 당신은 어디에 있나요?
You can't just take them out all at once.
한꺼번에 꺼낼 수는 없습니다.
I don't want to give you
나는 당신에게주고 싶지 않아요
so frightened, right?
너무 겁이 났죠?
Well,
잘,
both surprise and joy.
놀라움과 기쁨 둘 다.
What deal?
무슨 거래요?
I'll tell you when.
언제인지 말씀드리겠습니다.
But you have to remember
하지만 기억해야 해
what I told you in the car.
내가 차에서 말한 것.
The Japanese are unreliable now.
이제 일본인은 신뢰할 수 없습니다.
We have to think about our own future.
우리는 우리 자신의 미래에 대해 생각해야 합니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
When you opened the envelope,
봉투를 열어보니,
when you opened the envelope, right?
봉투를 열었을 때죠?
No, it's not.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
On the seal,
인감에는
was opened after being exposed to steam.
증기에 노출된 후 개봉되었습니다.
So it left no trace behind
그래서 흔적도 남지 않았어
chief Chen
첸 수석
I decided to be a good person
나는 좋은 사람이 되기로 결심했다
I'm still not used to it.
아직은 익숙하지 않아요.
I don't have much experience.
나는 경험이 많지 않습니다.
I need your advice.
당신의 조언이 필요합니다.
The second one.
두 번째.
The way you pretended to me
네가 나한테 그런 척 했던 방식
with your two pedicure blades.
두 개의 페디큐어 날로.
How he performed in front of me.
그가 내 앞에서 어떻게 공연했는지.
I never thought
나는 결코 생각하지 못했다
and become a good man again?
그리고 다시 좋은 사람이 될래?
That's right.
좋아요.
When I first came into the underworld,
처음 지하세계에 왔을 때,
I always think the world is so dangerous.
나는 항상 세상이 너무 위험하다고 생각한다.
One must refrain from evil deeds
악한 행위를 삼가해야 합니다
only by doing the most evil.
오직 가장 악한 일을 함으로써만.
But now she's a good person.
하지만 이제 그녀는 좋은 사람이 되었습니다.
Come in.
올.
Officer Uchida.
우치다 경관.
You are Qian Chengyi's
당신은 Qian Chengyi의 사람입니다.
yes
예
but everyone calls me Qian Xiucai.
그런데 다들 나를 Qian Xiucai라고 불러요.
You wrote the exposure letter?
폭로 편지를 썼나요?
Saying that Zhao An was actually killed by Luo Guanqun.
Zhao An은 실제로 Luo Guanqun에 의해 살해되었다고 말합니다.
Yes
예
although there is no direct evidence,
직접적인 증거는 없지만,
but I think it's a reasonable inference.
하지만 나는 그것이 합리적인 추론이라고 생각한다.
How long have you been in the reception office?
접수실에 얼마나 오래 있었나요?
More than two years.
2년 이상.
What exactly are you going to do?
정확히 무엇을 할 예정인가요?
Receiving and distributing newspapers and letters.
신문과 편지를 받고 배포합니다.
Look at this.
이거 봐요.
Tell me if you remember anything.
기억나는 것이 있으면 말해주세요.
Check the postmark.
소인을 확인하세요.
The sender's address should be around An De Road.
보내는 사람의 주소는 An De Road 주변이어야 합니다.
It could be anyone.
누구라도 될 수 있습니다.
To post a letter around An De Road.
An De Road 주변에 편지를 게시하려면.
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
You're right.
네가 옳아.
Officer.
장교.
Can I turn on the lamp?
램프를 켜도 될까요?
On
~에
this letter...
이 편지...
Is probably
아마도
from our firm.
우리 회사에서.
And mailed them.
그리고 그것을 우편으로 보냈습니다.
Why did you say that?
왜 그런 말을 했나요?
The envelope is made of cowhide paper.
봉투는 소가죽 종이로 만들어졌습니다.
The paper won't seep easily
종이가 쉽게 스며들지 않아요
good tenacity
좋은 끈기
It is the first choice for making the envelope.
봉투를 만들기 위한 첫 번째 선택입니다.
But there is a shortage of supplies these years.
하지만 올해는 공급이 부족합니다.
Now the available envelopes
이제 사용 가능한 봉투
have been replaced by cheap kraft paper.
저렴한 크라프트지로 교체했습니다.
Those who continue to use cored paper envelopes
계속해서 종이봉투를 사용하시는 분
are the departments and agencies
부서와 기관이다
that are working for the new government.
새 정부를 위해 일하는 사람들입니다.
It is said that this kind of paper
이런 종이라고 하네요
will not see through light.
빛을 통해 볼 수 없습니다.
And it is a strong secret
그리고 그것은 강력한 비밀이다
as for An De Road,
안드로드(An De Road)의 경우,
that work for the new government
그건 새 정부를 위해 일하는 거야
only Taihe Business Firm
유일한 태허 비즈니스 회사
It seems I got the right person.
제가 맞는 사람을 찾은 것 같습니다.
Please check the envelope.
봉투를 확인해 주세요.
Sir,
선생님,
this is confidential.
이것은 기밀입니다.
It's inappropriate with my position.
내 입장에는 부적절해요.
I think it's suitable.
나는 그것이 적합하다고 생각한다.
Yes
예
this movie is very boring,
이 영화는 매우 지루하다.
I suggest you not watch it.
시청하지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
I'm going to marry Yamashita Takeru.
나는 야마시타 타케루와 결혼할 예정이다.
Do you look down on me?
당신은 나를 무시합니까?
I wanted to escape.
나는 탈출하고 싶었다.
And I wanted to die.
그리고 나는 죽고 싶었습니다.
But then I decided to stay.
그러나 나는 머물기로 결정했습니다.
Jiang Zhaoguo wanted me to stay here.
Jiang Zhaoguo는 내가 여기에 머물기를 원했습니다.
But in the end, I've made this choice
하지만 결국 난 이런 선택을 했어
just for him.
그 사람을 위해서만.
Then for what?
그러면 무엇을 위해서?
I don't know either
나도 모르겠어요
I have sacrificed everything for him.
나는 그를 위해 모든 것을 희생했습니다.
My body
나의 몸
and my soul.
그리고 내 영혼.
And my dignity.
그리고 내 존엄성.
I did everything
나는 모든 것을 다했다
but I felt that I was wrong
하지만 난 내가 틀렸다고 느꼈어
totally wrong.
완전히 틀렸어.
Can I do something about it?
이에 대해 제가 뭔가를 할 수 있을까요?
What?
무엇?
I know I don't know you well.
나는 당신을 잘 모른다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
But my intuition tells me that
하지만 내 직감이 말해주잖아
you are not like them.
당신은 그들과 다릅니다.
I won't inquire about your identity.
당신의 신원에 대해서는 묻지 않겠습니다.
I just wanted to believe you.
나는 단지 당신을 믿고 싶었습니다.
So I think
그래서 나는 생각한다
If you can let me do something.
제가 뭔가를 하도록 허락해 주신다면요.
For a worthy reason,
합당한 이유로,
a noble faith.
고귀한 믿음.
In order to make my life
내 인생을 만들기 위해서는
to regain value,
가치를 되찾기 위해,
then...
그 다음에...
What do you want to do?
뭐하고 싶어?
Right now,
지금 바로,
who can get close to the warrior.
전사에게 가까이 다가갈 수 있는 사람.
He never told me his secrets.
그는 나에게 자신의 비밀을 말한 적이 없습니다.
But I know he is very powerful
하지만 나는 그가 매우 강력하다는 것을 안다.
and is planning something evil.
그리고 뭔가 나쁜 일을 계획하고 있어요.
Aren't you afraid of danger?
위험이 두렵지 않나요?
Not really.
설마.
Don't you fear that
당신은 그것을 두려워하지 마십시오
you'll lose the reputation
평판을 잃게 될 거야
or status,
또는 상태,
a halo?
그리고 안녕?
Don't be.
그러지 마세요.
I'm not afraid of death.
나는 죽음을 두려워하지 않습니다.
But I'm afraid of dying meaninglessly.
하지만 의미 없이 죽는 것은 두렵습니다.
Why are you back so late?
왜 이렇게 늦게 돌아왔나요?
Your superior replied to you.
당신의 상사가 당신에게 대답했습니다.
The application
응용 프로그램
I've submitted it to your organization.
귀하의 조직에 제출했습니다.
I can join your organization now.
나는 이제 당신의 조직에 합류할 수 있습니다.
Don't be anxious.
걱정하지 마세요.
Get me a glass of water.
물 한 잔 주세요.
The superior
우수한
asked me to investigate you
당신을 조사해 달라고 했어요
Investigate you for a while.
잠시 동안 당신을 조사하십시오.
You didn't get approved.
승인을 받지 못하셨어요.
Inspection doesn't mean you haven't approved.
검사가 승인되지 않았다는 의미는 아닙니다.
This is a serious and serious matter.
이것은 심각하고 심각한 문제입니다.
It's not all about your own will.
모든 것은 자기 뜻대로 되는 것이 아닙니다.
However,
하지만,
the organization has agreed
조직이 동의했다
to assist me with work.
내 일을 도와주려고.
So I can help you.
그래서 내가 당신을 도울 수 있습니다.
To support you?
당신을 지원하기 위해?
Luo Guanqun asked me
Luo Guanqun이 나에게 물었다.
he asked me to see him tomorrow morning.
그는 나에게 내일 아침에 만나자고 했습니다.
There must be something very important.
뭔가 아주 중요한 게 있을 거에요.
He asked you to rest for a while.
잠시 쉬어가라고 하더군요.
That means he needs me to the time.
그 말은 그 사람이 그때까지 내가 필요하다는 뜻이에요.
I'm thinking
나는 생각 중입니다
that he has got
그가 가지고 있는 것
the formula in Magpie's hands?
까치 손에 있는 공식은요?
I didn't expect that
나는 그것을 기대하지 않았다
jun Tong had a fight
준통이 싸웠어요
for the magpie for a while.
까치를 위해 잠시 동안.
Finally, they got caught behind.
마침내 그들은 뒤쳐졌습니다.
Luckily,
운 좋게,
luo Guanqun is just trying to get some leverage.
luo Guanqun은 단지 영향력을 행사하려고 노력하고 있습니다.
In this way, we'll get our chance.
이런 식으로 우리는 기회를 얻게 될 것입니다.
What is your plan?
당신의 계획은 무엇입니까?
Let me check first.
먼저 확인해 보겠습니다.
How Luo Guanqun dealt with Yamashita, right?
Luo Guanqun은 Yamashita를 어떻게 대했습니까?
And then choose the right opportunity.
그런 다음 적절한 기회를 선택하십시오.
I want to take part in the operation.
나는 그 수술에 참여하고 싶다.
According to your organization,
귀하의 조직에 따르면,
I can help you.
제가 도와드릴 수 있어요.
Alright.
괜찮은.
You finish reading those books first.
그 책들을 먼저 다 읽으세요.
Why do you read these?
왜 이것을 읽나요?
Actually, I was thinking that
사실 나도 그럴 생각이었는데
If Luo Guanqun might think this simple.
Luo Guanqun이 이것을 간단하게 생각할 수도 있습니다.
He wrote an anonymous letter
그는 익명으로 편지를 썼다
and made an anonymous phone call.
그리고 익명으로 전화를 걸었습니다.
And even bargain with her.
그리고 그녀와 흥정도 해보세요.
I don't believe that there is no strategy
전략이 없다고는 생각하지 않는다.
you are worried about exposing it.
노출될까봐 걱정되시죠?
If it is exposed,
노출된 경우,
luo Guanqun and I will be screwed.
Luo Guanqun과 나는 망할 것입니다.
But I still can't understand
하지만 난 아직도 이해가 안 돼요
what it has to do with reading these books.
이 책을 읽는 것과 무슨 관련이 있는지.
Tomorrow afternoon,
내일 오후,
tomorrow afternoon
내일 오후
to buy clothes for the wedding.
결혼식에 입을 옷을 사려고.
You'll go with Han Lu.
한루와 함께 가세요.
Found a place.
장소를 찾았습니다.
In the Gu House.
구 하우스에서.
A three-story Shikumen house.
3층짜리 시쿠멘 가옥.
It's secluded.
한적해요.
The line of sight is fine.
시선은 괜찮습니다.
Which is very convenient for us to monitor.
우리가 모니터링하는 데 매우 편리합니다.
One more thing.
하나 더.
I also connected a phone line
전화선도 연결했어요
to get there directly.
거기로 직접 가려면.
The phone company.
전화 회사.
We'll never find that location.
우리는 그 위치를 결코 찾지 못할 것입니다.
Take me there directly.
나를 그곳으로 직접 데려가 주세요.
All right.
괜찮은.
Manager Luo didn't come?
루 매니저님 안 오셨어요?
It's none of your business.
너와는 상관 없어.
Yes, that's right.
네, 맞습니다.
It's Mr. Luo's paper?
루오 씨의 논문인가요?
Section Chief Chen
첸 과장
are you here for work?
당신은 일하러 왔나요?
Right.
오른쪽.
So many things happened in the firm recently.
최근 회사에 정말 많은 일들이 일어났습니다.
I'm so glad to have you back.
당신을 다시 만나서 정말 기뻐요.
Right.
오른쪽.
We have fewer and fewer
우리는 점점 더 적어지고 있습니다.
In our business.
우리 사업에서.
That's right
좋아요
chief Chen
첸 수석
I've heard what happened to you
나는 당신에게 무슨 일이 있었는지 들었어요
It's really remarkable that
정말 놀라운 점은
you're really amazing.
당신은 정말 대단해요.
Why didn't you read your Chronicles of the States of Eastern Zhou?
당신은 왜 동주연대기를 읽지 않았습니까?
I've finished.
나는 끝냈다.
Finished.
완성된.
I thought you would watch it over and over again.
계속해서 지켜보실 거라고 생각했어요.
You don't need to read it over and over again
반복해서 읽을 필요는 없습니다
you don't have to read it over and over again?
반복해서 읽을 필요는 없나요?
Chief Chen
첸 수석
he's here
그는 여기에 있습니다
where is Luo?
루오는 어디 있지?
He's waiting for you.
그는 당신을 기다리고 있습니다.
Where is he?
그는 어디에 있나요?
He's not here.
그는 여기 없어.
Let me take you there.
내가 당신을 거기로 데려가겠습니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Drive the car.
운전을한다.
No, I won't.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
Don't drive.
운전하지 마세요.
Manager Luo said that
루 매니저가 그러더군요.
driving in and out.
운전하고 나가기.
Caught too much attention.
너무 많은 관심을 받았습니다.
Let's walk there.
거기로 걸어가자.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Who will that be?
그 사람은 누구일까요?
This place.
여기.
Why did Luo meet me here?
루오가 왜 여기서 나를 만났나요?
We'll find out after we enter.
들어가보고 나서 알아보겠습니다.
Is he in the room?
그 사람이 방에 있어요?
Yes, he's waiting for you.
네, 그 사람이 당신을 기다리고 있어요.
Brother,
형제,
what a shabby place this is!
여기 정말 초라한 곳이군요!
This is my command center.
여긴 내 지휘 센터야.
Knock it off.
집어 치워.
You don't have to command so shabby.
그렇게 초라하게 명령할 필요는 없어요.
Someone offered me a lot of money
누군가 나에게 많은 돈을 제안했다
to buy the thing I have
내가 가지고 있는 것을 사려고
what's that
그게 뭐야?
the formula of coin paper
동전 종이의 공식
I heard about it.
나는 그것에 대해 들었습니다.
Why do you have it?
왜 가지고 있나요?
We are the only ones
우리는 유일한 사람이다
only you and I,
너와 나만,
big spoon.
큰 숟가락.
The three of us know it.
우리 셋은 그걸 알고 있어요.
If the deal goes down,
거래가 무산되면,
our heads
우리 머리
land on the ground together.
함께 땅에 착륙합니다.
Brother,
형제,
we've done so much business.
우리는 너무 많은 사업을 해왔습니다.
Why do we have to be killed this time?
이번에는 왜 우리가 죽임을 당해야 합니까?
Do you know who you made deals with this time?
이번에 누구랑 거래했는지 아세요?
Who?
WHO?
Martial arts master under the mountain.
산 아래 무술의 달인.
Martial Master of the Mountain.
산의 무술가.
Scared?
무서운?
Chief Chen
첸 수석
you can't leave?
떠날 수 없어?
You've already known too much.
당신은 이미 너무 많은 것을 알고 있었습니다.
Come here.
이리 오세요.
Have a seat
앉으세요
chief Chen
첸 수석
and let Manager Luo finish.
Luo 감독님이 마치도록 하세요.
Well, brother.
글쎄, 형제.
I'm just a pawn on the stage.
나는 무대 위의 졸개일 뿐이다.
I can't sing in this play.
나는 이 연극에서 노래를 부를 수 없다.
Stop that
그만
you managed to escape from the detention center of the Military Police Headquarters.
당신은 헌병사령부 구류장에서 가까스로 탈출했습니다.
You should do this.
이렇게 해야 합니다.
Ten big yellow croaker,
10개의 큰 노랑 민어,
ten fishes?
물고기 열 마리?
Or yellow croaker?
아니면 노랑 민어?
I can't do that either.
나도 그렇게 할 수 없습니다.
My life is ruined.
내 인생은 망가졌습니다.
What's the use of money?
돈이 무슨 소용이 있나요?
You know what?
그거 알아?
As long as you use your wits,
당신이 지혜를 사용하는 한,
you'll be able to do it.
당신은 그것을 할 수있을 것입니다.
Then brother,
그럼 형,
what do you want me to do?
내가 무엇을 하기를 바라나요?
You know
알잖아
about the current situation?
현재 상황에 대해?
In the future,
미래에,
more and more miserable.
점점 더 비참해집니다.
You don't want to
당신은 원하지 않습니다
end up in a corner?
결국 구석에?
I don't want to.
나는 원하지 않는다.
The Japanese are not reliable anymore.
일본인은 더 이상 신뢰할 수 없습니다.
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Can I rely on money?
돈에 의지할 수 있나요?
Money every day.
매일 돈.
Soon the money will become a pile of waste paper.
곧 돈은 폐지 더미가 될 것입니다.
Gold
금
you can only count on holding gold.
당신은 금을 보유하는 것만 믿을 수 있습니다.
Aren't you afraid of the Japanese collapsing?
일본이 무너지는 것이 두렵지 않습니까?
Aren't you scared?
두렵지 않나요?
The Communists are back against us. Are you scared?
공산주의자들이 우리에게 돌아왔습니다. 너 두렵 니?
Aren't you scared that the National Army is back?
국군이 돌아오는 게 두렵지 않으신가요?
Or not?
아니면?
Let the moon shine on the lakes.
호수에 달이 빛나게 해주세요.
Don't be afraid that you can catch the golden hook anywhere.
어디에서나 황금 갈고리를 잡을 수 있다는 것을 두려워하지 마십시오.
Enough!
충분한!
Brother. Brother. Brother. Brother.
형제. 형제. 형제. 형제.
Stop reciting your stupid poem.
멍청한 시를 낭송하지 마세요.
What the hell do you want me to do?
도대체 내가 무엇을 하기를 바라나요?
My good friend.
나의 좋은 친구.
These words
이 단어
are from "Liang You."
"양유" 출신이에요.
Then this person
그럼 이 사람
he will be one of those who subscribed to Good Friend.
그는 Good Friend를 구독하는 사람 중 한 명일 것입니다.
How is the investigation going?
조사는 어떻게 진행되고 있나요?
No news yet.
아직 소식이 없습니다.
What's the name of the person
그 사람 이름이 뭐예요?
you mentioned before?
아까 말했지?
Is Qian Chengyi
Qian Chengyi인가?
are you sure that
그거 확실해?
he'll be able to find out the truth?
과연 그는 진실을 알아낼 수 있을까요?
If he is in Taihe Trading Firm,
만약 그가 태화무역회사에 있다면,
he knows that everyone there
그 사람은 거기 있는 사람들이 다 알아요
you have to believe that some people will stop at nothing
어떤 사람들은 아무것도 하지 않을 것이라고 믿어야 합니다
to go upwards.
위로 가기 위해.
I'm going to prepare the kimono
기모노를 준비할 거예요
to prepare the kimono for the wedding.
결혼식을 위해 기모노를 준비합니다.
Once we have something,
일단 뭔가가 생기면,
call Juchuan Riqiao Shop immediately.
즉시 Juchuan Riqiao Shop에 전화하세요.
Yes
예
mr Yamashita
mr Yamashita
has brought Miss Han Lu here.
한루 선생님을 여기로 데려왔습니다.
She's waiting for you outside.
그녀는 밖에서 당신을 기다리고 있습니다.
I shouldn't have let such a beautiful lady
이렇게 아름다운 여자를 놔두지 말았어야 했는데
I should have done it.
내가 했어야 했는데.
Mr. Yamashita,
Mr. Yamashita,
what's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
That man called again.
그 사람이 또 전화했어요.
He wants to make a deal today.
그는 오늘 거래를 하고 싶어합니다.
Time and place
시간과 장소
how to conduct the transaction?
거래를 어떻게 진행하나요?
There is a public phone booth beside Pacific Music Store
퍼시픽 뮤직 스토어 옆에 공중전화 부스가 있습니다.
near Pacific Music Store on Waima Road
Waima Road의 Pacific Music Store 근처
he asked you to go there alone.
그는 당신에게 거기 혼자 가라고 요청했습니다.
Wait for him to call you there at 3 p.m.
그 사람이 오후 3시에 그곳으로 전화할 때까지 기다리세요
You are going alone.
당신은 혼자 가고 있습니다.
That's too dangerous.
그건 너무 위험해요.
He also said
그는 또한 말했다
he will be watching nearby.
그 사람이 근처에서 지켜보고 있을 거예요.
Once you find someone is with you,
누군가가 당신과 함께 있다는 것을 발견하면,
cancel the deal.
거래를 취소하세요.
I will arrange good people in advance
좋은 사람들을 미리 준비하겠습니다.
around the phone booth
전화부스 주변
tell them to never hide
절대 숨지 말라고 말해
and don't be discovered.
그리고 발견되지 마십시오.
Yes
예
however,
하지만,
according to my judgment,
내 판단에 따르면,
the real exchange place
진짜 교환 장소
wasn't that phone booth
저거 전화부스 아니었어?
he still changes his address.
그는 아직도 주소를 바꾼다.
I'll pretend to follow him
따라가는 척 할게요
to protect you.
당신을 보호하기 위해.
Catch the blackmailer at the same time.
협박범을 동시에 잡아보세요.
Remember that
기억
the formula is the most important,
공식이 가장 중요하고,
the most important part is catching him.
가장 중요한 부분은 그를 잡는 것입니다.
Yes
예
put the gold in the car.
금을 차에 넣으세요.
what about
~는 어때
my beautiful Miss Han Lu.
나의 아름다운 한루 선생님.
Have you found your favorite style?
마음에 드는 스타일을 찾으셨나요?
Your eyes are blind.
당신의 눈은 멀었습니다.
I must go to the store
가게에 가야 해요
and try it on in person.
직접 입어보세요.
I'm very sorry.
나는 매우 미안 해요.
Something came up.
뭔가 떠올랐어요.
I won't accompany you now.
나는 이제 당신과 동행하지 않을 것입니다.
But don't worry.
하지만 걱정하지 마세요.
As soon as I'm done,
끝나자마자,
I'll come and keep you company.
내가 가서 당신과 함께 있어줄게요.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Luckily, I have an appointment with Zuo Shuangtao.
운 좋게도 Zuo Shuangtao와 약속이 있습니다.
I won't be alone anymore.
나는 더 이상 혼자가 아닙니다.
Left Shuangtao.
왼쪽 Shuangtao.
From Taihe Trading Firm?
태허무역회사에서요?
Right.
오른쪽.
Her husband Chen Jiaping is my good friend.
그녀의 남편 Chen Jiaping은 나의 좋은 친구입니다.
She knows Japanese kimono culture very well.
그녀는 일본의 기모노 문화를 아주 잘 알고 있습니다.
She can give me advice.
그녀는 나에게 조언을 해줄 수 있습니다.
That you are willing to wear a kimono
기모노를 입을 의향이 있다는 것
I'm really
나는 정말로
I'm very pleased.
나는 매우 기쁘게 생각합니다.
There're too many people.
사람이 너무 많아요.
We can't investigate one by one
일일이 조사할 수 없어
mr. Yamashita,
mr. Yamashita,
the outer road is ahead.
외부 도로가 앞에 있습니다.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
This is Underhill.
언더힐입니다.
Five minutes from now,
지금부터 5분,
there is a phone booth
전화 부스가 있어요
telephone booth.
전화 부스.
If you are late,
늦었다면,
the deal is off.
거래가 끝났습니다.